Guide to the Frank Alfred Golder Papers, 1858-1927
Department of Special Collections
Frank Alfred Golder Papers,
1858-1927
Special Collections M0199
Golder, Frank Alfred
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Transfer from Hoover Archives, 1970
Biography
American historian of Russia and the Russian sphere of influence in North America.
Scope and Content
Summary: Correspondence, notes, documents and typescripts relating primarily to Russia's presence in North America.
Container List
- 1919Typed Correspondence (Folder 1)
  - 1. Emily B. Mitchell to the Chief of the Manuscript Division, Library of Congress. Typed Memo
  - 2. List of Transcripts from Russian Archives obtained for the Library of Congress by F.A. Golder
  - 3. Charles MOon to Dr. F.A. Golder. T.L.S.
- 1927, June 1Certificate of Compoletion of Prescribed Course of Study in the American Methodist Gimnasium, Real Section, Harbin, China. ( In Russian and Chinese) (Folder 2)
- 1903-1904Russian printed pamphlets concerning commercial navigation (Folder 3)
- 1858, Aug. 2Extract of some of the Act of Administration of British Columbia. (In Russian) (Folder 4)
- Notes in Russian concerning the Hudson's Bay Company. (Folder 5)
- Notes in Russian concerning the Russian-American Company (Folder 6)
- Typed Biliography (In Russian) 2 copies pertaining to the exploration of teh Russian Far East (Folder 7)
- Unidentified Documents (In Russian) (Folder 8)
- Documents in French (Folder 9)
  - 1. Typed notes concerning St. Petersbourg in 1764 and 1765.
  - 2. Address given to the History and Philology Section of the Imperial Academy of Science (1861, Jan. 18)
- Photographs (Folder 10)
  - 1. Document relating to Bering's First Expedition with comments by Peter.
  - 2. Map of route from Judowa Cross to Okhotsk
- Intro to second part of the "On the Volga" By Iu Smel'nitshii [?]- typescript (Folder 11)